SUMMARY

Operations Analyst and Administrator experience of 15+ years, with a focus of project management and interdepartment relationship liaison. Built a reputation for time management and meeting critical deadlines. Facilitate training for personnel of systems and quality control oversight for local and national systems.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR OPERATIONS ANALYST GANNETT COMPANY, INC.

Phoenix, AZ 9/2005 - Current

- Internal support for 10,000+ employees of desktop software and hardware concerns
- Primary support and organizer for Windows Server Update Services (WSUS) and System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM) environment: implementation, scheduling and processing
- Experience managing IBM iSeries and Microsoft Windows platforms: software and hardware
- Administrate, schedule and troubleshoot batch processing for all USA TODAY print sites and field operators
- Manage batch scheduling for Circulation and Advertising as determined by company commitments
- Create, organize, and maintain IBM iSeries backup jobs and schedules, and the Backup Recovery and Media Services (BRMS) onsite and offsite
- Organize and manage the storage of Operations, Midrange, and USA TODAY equipment for Phoenix, Arizona
- Create, maintain and test document support for Gannett Operations and USA TODAY operations
- Detail and organize job efforts for Gannett Operations staff
- Education and management of the Robot and Halcyon job scheduling systems
- Operational support and control for IBM Hardware Management Console (HMC), Symantec NetBackup and McAfee ePolicy Orchestrator 4.6
- Train Operations staff on systems procedures and tasks for the IBM iSeries and Microsoft Windows platform
- Exposure to SQL code and CL code using the IBM iSeries and Microsoft Windows platforms
- Research and implement new technologies for use within Gannett Operations to increase business efficiency
- Troubleshoot issues in the following areas: Exchange, Active Directory account management and security
- Recognized for: USA TODAY National Support, Helpdesk Support, Project Management, and Training

OPERATIONS SPECIALIST

PHOENIX NEWSPAPERS, INC.

Phoenix, AZ 12/2003 - 9/2005

- Internal support for 1,500+ employees of desktop software and hardware concerns
- Quality control of daily, weekly, and monthly state news media files
- Oversee daily batch scheduling and execute escalation policies to ensure production objectives are met
- Provide efficient communication across multiple departments to resolve customer and production issues

COMPUTER OPERATOR I

ARIZONA FEDERAL CREDIT UNION

Phoenix, AZ

1/2003 - 12/2003

- Monitor system software to locate and remedy system anomalies
- Address and troubleshoot employee software and phone system issues
- Oversee and implement business improvements of report generation and system processes
- Support external member system processes: ATM, shared branching, credit reporting, phone and internet
- Maintain backup of all Credit Union financial data

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA

9/2018 - Present (3/2019)

PHOENIX, AZ

The Coding Bootcamp (Continuing and Professional Education)

UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX

5/2007 - 12/2010

PHOENIX, AZ

- Bachelor of Science in Information Technology/Information Systems Security
- Associate in Arts of Information Technology/Networking

MESA COMMUNITY COLLEGE

5/2004 - 5/2007

MESA, AZ

3rd Semester Computer Information Systems

UNIVERSITY OF ADVANCING COMPUTER

2000 - 2002

TEMPE, AZ

15-month study in Application Design and Systems Programming

INSTITUTE OF FINANCIAL EDUCATION

1997 - 1999 Teller Operations

NORTH AUGUSTA, SC

Individual Retirement Accounts

Communications Sales Excellence

Consumer Lending Business

Deposit Accounts and Services